They wanted gold. They gave them lead instead!
Big Jake is a western film directed by George Sherman.
An aging Texas cattle man who has outlived his time swings
into action when outlaws kidnap his grandson.
Jacob McCandles, played by John Wayne.
John Fain, played by Richard Boone.
Martha McCandles, played by Maureen O'Hara.
James McCandles, played by Patrick Wayne.
Michael McCandles, played by Christopher Mitchum.
Jeff McCandles, played by Bobby Vinton.
Big Jake is a 1971 American Technicolor Western film starring
John Wayne, Richard Boone and Maureen O'Hara.
The picture was the final film for George Sherman in a directing career of more than 30 years, and
Maureen O'Hara's last film with John Wayne and her last before her twenty-year retirement.
The supporting cast features Patrick Wayne, Christopher Mitchum,
Glenn Corbett, Jim Davis, John Agar, Harry Carey Jr.
and Hank Worden.
The film explores themes of kidnapping, texas, ranch, cigar smoking.